so let's look at the sizes of some
actual virtually indexed physically
tagged caches while doing the previous
quiz we have figured out that the cache
size needs to be less than or equal to
the associativity of the cache times the
page size so if we look at for example
the Intel Pentium 4 processor it has a
4-way set associative cache and a page
size of 4 kilobytes and it's level 1
cache is 16 kilobytes the more recent
court to Nehalem Sandy Bridge and
Haswell processors from Intel R 8 weight
set associative of course they still
have the 4 kilobyte page size and
surprise surprise the level 1 cache is
32 kilobytes the upcoming skylight
design from Intel is rumored to be 16
Way set associative and you guessed it
it's rumored to have a 64 kilobyte level
1 cache